# **Phil Vigus**

# Software Developer

www.philvigus.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/philvigus

github.com/PhilipVigus

#### **PROFILE**

After qualifying with a degree in Computer Science, I spent much of my career working in technology and education. A few years ago I completed the Maker's Academy coding bootcamp before becoming Software Developer at Mumsnet. I recently moved to Stockholm where I now work as a Backend Consultant specialising in Java and JavaScript with AWS.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages - Java, JavaScript/TypeScript, PHP Frameworks and libraries - Spring Boot, Hibernate, Serverless Framework, Laravel, Livewire, React

**Databases** - SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis, MongoDB **Dev-Ops/CI/CD** - AWS, Terraform, Github Actions,

Docker, Heroku, DigitalOcean **Other** - Testing/TDD, Git, Agile/Scrum, OOP,

**RESTful APIs** 

#### **CERTIFICATES**

**AWS Associate Solutions Architect ☑** 2022

### **PROJECTS**

#### Database entity factories **2**

Allows you to easily create and persist entities with random but logical attributes using Spring Boot and Hibernate.

#### Wibbly 2

A URL shortener written using Spring Boot.

#### Film follower 🛮

Designed to help shortlist films to watch. Written using Tailwind, Alpine, Laravel and Livewire.

#### **KEY PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Backend Developer/Consultant,** $Devoteam \square$

09/2022 - present | Stockholm, Sweden

- Completing the migration of a client's key application from using MySQL to a MongoDB database
- Maintaining a complex legacy codebase utilising AWS (Lambda, Step Functions, SQS, SNS, API Gateway, CloudFormation etc) and integrations with a large number of external systems
- Building an IoT project to control the air quality in meeting rooms
- Supporting business development by providing technical input to bid documents and estimates

# **Backend Java Developer,** *The Climate App* ☑ 10/2022 – present | Remote

- Lead developer on the administration and user management system
- Implementing new features and maintaining the main application backend

#### **Developer,** *Mumsnet* □

11/2020 - 08/2022 | London, UK

- Writing and optimising scripts to migrate large amounts of data from a legacy database, reducing runtime from five days to three hours
- Implementing a new CMS, reducing the time taken to create an article from two hours to half an hour
- Developing the main talk forum and admin system
- Mentoring and onboarding new team members

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

#### Communication

Working in multi-disciplinary teams and clientfacing roles at Devoteam, Mumsnet and OCN London.

### **Problem solving**

Designing and implementing features at Devoteam and Mumsnet, working with assistive technology at The National Star College.

#### High emotional intelligence

Mentoring, pair programming and doing code reviews at Mumsnet, and empathising with diverse clients at OCN London and Aspire.

# ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

# **Welfare Benefits Administrator,** *Aspire* 02/2018 – 07/2018

- First point of contact for often distressed clients, using empathy to help them understand available and appropriate services
- Communicating across multi-disciplinary teams to ensure work with clients was consistent

# Senior Administration Officer then Quality Reviewer, OCNLR

04/2007 - 10/2012

- Managing a caseload of 150+ educational centres across London, using strong interpersonal skills to develop relationships with clients and grow their business
- Working with centres to improve their quality utilising strong problem-solving skills to identify and resolve issues
- Writing detailed reports and handling complex queries using excellent communication skills
- Delivering training to colleagues and clients using teamwork and high levels of empathy

### IT Access Technical Developer and ICT Teacher,

The National Star College

09/2004 - 11/2006

- Evaluating and solving problems with learners' assistive technology needs, and training them to use their equipment
- Training staff and teaching students using my technical knowledge and understanding of how people learn

### **Research Scientist,** *QinetiQ*

07/2000 - 08/2003

Building computer simulations using my problem-solving and technical skills

#### **Software Developer,** *Quidnunc*

07/1999 - 01/2000

• Building e-commerce websites

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Software Development,** *Maker's Academy*

2020

A 16-week intensive programming bootcamp

## **PGCE (ICT),** Exeter University

2004

A postgraduate certificate in education, specialising in Information and Communication Technologies

#### **BSc.** (Hons) Computer Science (2:1),

The University of Nottingham

1996 - 1999

#### **LANGUAGES**

### English (native speaker)

#### **Swedish (beginner)**

Evening classes at City of Westminster University